LOREN LISK

loren.lisk@liskl.com

154 Black Hickory Way, Ormond Beach FL 32174

678.871.9354

Career Summary

Summary: IT Professional with over 10 years of diversified experience including: Virtualization, Linux System Administration and Engineering, Network and Database Administration, Seeking an Organization where I can contribute value by optimization & design of existing and future infrastructure, preferably in a high career path in DevOps and automation in a linux based environment.

Core Compentancy / Skills

Virtualization: KVM/VMWare/XEN/AWS/OpenStack Linux: (Ubuntu/RHEL) Containerization: Kubernetes/Docker/LXC Programming: (Bash/Python/PHP/HTML5/CSS3) Configuration Management: (Salt/Ansible/Puppet) Devops Tools: (Jenkins/Git) Distributed Monitoring: (Check_MK/Nagios/ELK) Business Intelligence: (BIA/HANA) SAN: (EMC/SolidFire/ZFS) Infrastructure Applications: (DNS/DHCP/ELK) Middle Tier Applications: (MySQL/redis) Frontend Applications: (Apache/Nginx)

Many other skills are known and/or can be learned quickly

Work Experience

Senior DevOps Engineer III, Engineering

FoghornConsulting in San Francisco, CA

Aug 2017 - present

- Kubernetes SME, Senior authority and Escalation point for Kubernetes and containerization, for all Clients, Internal and External
- Technical Lead on Multiple Customers
- Developed Training for Kubernetes, for the engineering and consulting Teams to provide competant support and helped document the best practices
- Supported upwards of 30 kubernetes clusters and architected 12+ of them personally
- Established and Maintained Great Relationships with Our Customers
- wrote technical documentation as well as technical blog posts as a thought leader
- Helped support a growing list of Fortune 500 Clients with implementation and architectural containerization consultation
- Completed multiple modernization efforts into containerization and kubernetes orchestration

Senior Linux Systems Engineer III, Operations Engineering

Jul 2015 - Aug 2017

Peak Hosting / Peak Consulting Services in Tualitin, OR

- Final Escalation point for Complex, non-routine technical challenges to our external Customers
- Closely Collaborate with Storage, Networking, Software Engineering Teams
- Train tier 2 to provide competant support and helped document the best practices / documentation Deploy Custom "One-Off" products / projects when required and approved Established and Maintained Great Relationships with Our Customers / Vendors
- Wrote Deployment kickstarts / preseeds and validation Scripts for customer Complex Deployments
- Supported 5 Datacenters Containing 8000+ Servers
- Completed a 2300 Server DC Migration, including P2V moving them cross country within 30 days, Averaging 10m of Downtime per Host in parallel. Deployed an Production OpenStack (Mitaka) Deployment for Private Cloud use.

Senior Linux Systems Administrator III, Customer Dedicated Team

Nov 2014 - Jul 2015

Peak Hosting / Peak Consulting Services in Tualitin, OR

- Developed Training Material to Support/deploy the infrastructure for a Massively Multiplayer Mobile Game rated in the Top 10 Designed and Supported an LLDP Deployment Across 4000 Servers within very tight timelines
- Deployed Redis HA Clusters & MySQL HA Clusters using Galera and Percona as well as massive frontend nginx web heads behind VIPS
- Provided Personalized High Availible Tier III Support for Customer in the > \$1 Million Monthly Revenue Range Worked closely with all support teams regarding the Customer and Mantained Quality of Service
- Helped Defined the Change Management Regarding the Customer Supported 5 Datacenters Containing 7000 Servers

Senior Linux Systems Administrator III, Customer Support

Apr 2014 - Nov 2014

Peak Hosting / Peak Consulting Services in Tualitin, OR

- Front Line Tier III Support handling all Tasks that could be handled within Customer Support
- Became Subject Matter Expert regarding Linux Support within the Customer Support Department Supported 3 Datacenters Containing 3000 Servers

Senior Linux Systems Administrator III, Customer Support

May 2013 - Apr 2014

IBM, ISDC BIA/HANA Support in Atlanta, GA

- Final Escalation point in the US for HANA / BIA Support Clients, including 10+ Fortune 500 Customers.
- Helped Develop, Maintain and Support SAP BIA/HANA Business Intelligence Deployment Clusters Deployed 75 Rack HANA Distributed Performance Metric Gathering using Graphana

Senior, Linux Systems Administrator III

Jun 2012 - June 2013

Peer 1 Hosting, Network Enterprises in Atlanta, GA

• Tier 3 Support handling the Complex Tasks supporting 8 Datacenters and 21 POP's holding 21,000+ servers.

Work Experience - Continued

Junior, Linux Systems Administrator II

Jan 2012 - June 2012

Peer 1 Hosting, Network Enterprises in Atlanta, GA

• Tier 2 Support handling the Complex Tasks supporting 8 Datacenters and 21 POP's holding 8,000+ servers.

Technology Support Technician

Feb 2010 - Feb 2012

Chattahoochee Technical College in Marietta, GA

Resolved Technical issues in a multi-city / multi Campus Higher Learning Institution.

Federal Work Study

Oct 2009 - Feb 2010

Chattahoochee Technical College in Marietta, GA

• Resolved Technical issues in a multi-city / multi Campus Higher Learning Institution.

Store Manager Radioshack in Marietta, GA

Feb 2008 - Jul 2008

• Managerial duties and Maintaining profitability while handling employee and customer support and happiness.

Technology Specialist

Apr 2007 - Jan 2008

Officemax in Marietta, GA

• The Store Technology Specialist is responsible for driving sales and profitability by providing personalized guidance to consumers to help identify and qualify the appropriate technology solution to meet the customer's needs. This position also serves as the in-store expert for technically related questions and supports sales and marketing activities for all areas within the store. In addition, this position performed Manager on Duty responsibilities.

Shift Manager Sept 2002 - Apr 2007

McDonald's in Marietta, GA

· Managed and maintained the work environment for McDonalds Corporation and helped improve the bottom line while maintaining a happy place for people to work.

Education Summary

- (Amazon Web Services, Certified Associate Solutions Architect: AWS-ASA-23858, in 2016)
- (Associates in Networking from Chattahoochee Technical Collage of GA, in 2007)
- (CIS CCNA Certificate from Chattahoochee Technical Collage of GA, in 2004)
- (Renewed A+/Net+/Sec+ from Comptia in 2011)
- Mostly Self Taught, I'm a Quick Study with a firm grasp of the Abstract Knowledge and a home lab.

Professional Reccomendations

• Justin Harris, Network Engineer, Peak Hosting, worked with Loren at Peak Hosting

"Loren is one of the strongest Linux engineers I have ever had the pleasure to work with. His dedication and passion helped drive all of our projects together to completion, even under very tight time lines. Loren is always willing to help, teach, and learn, making him a rock star in any team. I would highly recommend!"

• Adam Sully, Lead Technical Account Manager, Peak Web Hosting, worked with Loren at Peak Hosting

"Loren was an excellent addition to our engineering team. He was very knowledgable, results driven, and detail oriented. He was always willing to go the extra mile during times of increased operational tempo and was willing to dive into complex issues to help his team mates succeed. It was a pleasure to work with Loren and I'd love to work with him again in the future."

Syn Calvo, Operations Engineer & Product Owner, Peak Hosting, worked directly with Loren at Peak Hosting

"For almost two and a half years, I had the honor of working with Loren first as a Linux System Administrator and then through the creation of a new team of Operations Engineers. Loren's knowledge and expertise were invaluable to me at Peak Hosting and he is one of the best team members I could have asked for. He is always willing to help and would seek every opportunity to trade knowledge and learn or teach something new. He is never afraid to receive honest feedback and turn advice into profit or work with his team toward a mutual solution for customer inquiries. Loren's involvement in and understanding of Linux Administration, Problem Management and Change Management brought me to him many times for advice. He is an asset to any company looking for a rock star on their team."

Professional Reccomendations - Continued

• Richard Staats, MBA, Operations Engineer (Systems Engineer II), Peak Hosting, worked directly with Loren at Peak Hosting

"Loren is undoubtedly one of the most talented Linux Engineers I have ever worked with. It has been my pleasure working with Loren for the past year and learning all kinds of awesome new things from him. As a true Linux professional Loren is always eager to dissect complex problems and where possible automate solutions to make work faster, more accurate, and repeatable. With an insatiable passion for learning and diving deep into new tech, Loren is truly a master of his craft. "

• John Biggi, President, Peak Hosting, managed Loren indirectly at Peak Hosting

"Loren has been a consistent technical lead within Peak's Operations team. Loren has been integral in creating and delivering the content of various internal training sessions. Loren has also been at the forefront of creating processes and procedures which enabled our teams to be more efficient and effective in their delivery of services for Peak's customers. Loren's technical skills are consistently sought after by his peers as well as his cross functional teammates. I would recommend Loren for any position that requires both technical prowess as well as excellent interpersonal skills."

 Fereydoun Tavangary, MBA, Customer Support Director/Operation Engineering Manager, Peak Hosting, managed Loren at Peak Hosting

"It has been my pleasure to supervise Loren at Peak Hosting. I found him to be a hard worker, he always kept calm under pressure and I could count on him to be a natural leader. He always went above and beyond his job duties and was willing to step up and take on new challenges to help his team be successful. Loren has excellent communication skills, strong technical abilities, is organized, multi-tasks efficiently and can work well independently."

· Ryan King, Lead Client-dedicated Systems Administrator, Peak Hosting, worked directly with Loren at Peak Hosting

"Loren was one of the brightest points of my time with Peak Hosting. His interest and professional input into many areas in a high-volume, high-pressure environment were constantly helpful in making sure that everything was running smoothly. Loren's experience and guidance were invaluable in helping to formulate most of our policies and procedures in dealing with large and complex customers, and his leadership was essential in guiding our team to meet ever-changing and increasingly difficult goals. Loren proved himself time and time again to be a valuable asset to any project he was asked to handle."

· Pavel May, System Administrator, Peak Hosting, worked directly with Loren at Peak Hosting

"Loren is a detail-oriented, untiring, ceaselessly efficiency-minded, automation-loving Linux administrator. No task seems too big, but also no task beneath him. Loren always seeks out feedback on which to base his improvement. An utter pleasure to work with this man."

• Deon Rodden, Operations Engineer, Peak Hosting, worked directly with Loren at Peak Hosting

"You won't find a more dedicated geek than Loren. I mean Geek an an awesome, amazing way. He's passionate about technology, always trying new things and learning new things, always going above and beyond the call of duty. He's a dedicated, hard working Linux guru who doesn't do this just because it's a job, but because it's his passion, and it shows. If you always want to know about the latest and greatest technology, chances are Loren's testing it on his home lab. Highly recommended."

Professional Reccomendations - Continued

• Jim Butler, Linux System Administrator 3, BWA SAP Support, Lenovo, worked directly with Loren at IBM

"To whom it may concern, I have worked with Loren Lisk at IBM, and I was extremely impressed with Loren's level of knowledge and his exceptional enthusiasm. Mr. Lisk brought a wealth of knowledge and skill that helped us improve the efficiency and effectiveness of our Managed Services offering. Key areas of expertise in which Loren contributed included Linux administration, BASH scripting, hardware platform knowledge, and several proposals for new solutions to help make our operation more efficient. Loren's knowledge includes a well rounded set of skills at expert levels, only some of which are within the scope of what our team does. Any company would gain an extreme value if they choose to hire Loren Lisk as System Administrator . Regards, Donald Butler "

 William Bakke, Server Support Specialist, IBM Integrated Service Delivery Center (ISDC), worked directly with Loren at IBM

"Loren Lisk is extremely dedicated, able to work great in a team or by himself on task, thrives under pressure. Always keeping his skills updated and remaining top of his game, given a new project he will learn everything he needs to know to not only complete the task but improve on it."

• Michael Gardner, Senior Manager Technical Support, Peer 1 Hosting, managed Loren at PEER 1 Hosting

"Loren is one of the best Linux administrators I know. He is extremely knowledgeable in Linux, Networking and server administration. When I had the pleasure of being his leader, her stood out as the go to guy shortly after joining the company. I was impressed with how hard he worked to learn our business and master it. I constantly received great compliments and kudos our customers about him. I had customers that he impressed who only wanted to work with him. If you are looking for a hard working, knowledgeable administrator who is great with his team and customers, Loren is the person."

• Brian Beaudoin, Product Engineer IV, Peer 1 Hosting, worked with Loren at PEER 1 Hosting

"Loren has always been a pleasure to work with. As an outgoing, communicative coworker, he naturally gets along with others lending his strengths to others in teams. His drive to continuously learn and improve has deepened his breadth of knowledge and experience in cloud technologies, immutable deployments, and orchestration for scalability and management. I wholeheartedly give him my recommendation."

• Scott Billups, Lead Supervisor, Peer 1 Network Enterprises, Inc., managed Loren indirectly at PEER 1 Hosting

"Loren has incredible Linux skills that can contribute to any organization. His sense of urgency and working great under pressures separates him from the pack of systems administrators / engineers. If I had the opportunity work with or hire Loren, I would so in a heart beat."

• Clarence Winfield, managed Loren at Chattahoochee Technical College

"Loren is very technical and knowlegeable of his position and many other aspects and areas of the Technical Support division of Chattahoochee Technical College. Not only does he performs his primary duties efficiently and promptly, his performance is the same or better when assigned to or volunteers to help with other projects. He is always trying/willing to learn more and is constantly getting training for and works hard at earning various IT certifications. Working with Loren has also increased my knowledge in some ares of IT."

• Victoria Gardner, managed Loren indirectly at Chattahoochee Technical College

"As a Federal Work Study, Loren put in more hours than required under the program, often keeping the pace of many of the full time staff. His diversity in the technology field, gained as much under personal experience as education, made him a great asset during his time in our support department. Problem solving is among his many strengths. Not afraid of a challenge, Loren took his personal time to "tweak" existing applications, making them more efficient, faster, saving time and resources. He is supportive of other people's ideas and will offer to help to bring about the best results."